(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
沙花叉アリソンフェス、スタート！
Sakamata Allison Fes, start!
プリキュア！
Pretty Cure!
プリティで
Prettily
キュアキュア！
Cure Cure!
ふたりはプリキュア！
We are Pretty Cure!
一難去って また一難
Out of the frying pan and into the fire
ぶっちゃけありえない！
I seriously can't believe it!
制服着ててもふたりは
Even when wearing uniforms, we are
むちゃくちゃタフだし！
Incredibly tough!
お互いピンチを乗り越えるたび
Every time we overcome a crisis together
強く
Stronger
近く
Closer
なるね！
We become!
Your best! My best!
生きてるんだから
Because we're alive
失敗なんてメッチャしちゃえ！
Go ahead and fail as much as you want!
笑う門に福来るでしょ！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
ネガティブだってぶっ飛ぶよ！
Even negativity will be blown away!
命の花 咲かせて 思い切り
Make the flower of life bloom with all your might
もっとバリバリ！
Even more vigorously!
プリキュア！
Pretty Cure!
Hey everybody!
Yeah!
Are you ready?
Let's go!
Counteraction rising
Yeah we are ready for the punch line
There's no use with all your gimmicks
SO CHECK THIS OUT!
Login you damn once crush the won't you compromise
The noise comes we are ready to bow
What about the antidote for the jammed and hypnotized
Rend the live it comes the real sucker
咲き乱れた花のように
Like flowers blooming profusely
鮮やかな痛み抱き
Embracing the vivid pain
佇む街を抜けて
Passing through the standing city
迷いのセリフは捨て
Discarding the words of hesitation
帰らない声よ響け
Let the voice that won't return resonate
3分前だよみんなー！
3 minutes left, everyone!
あ、緊張していますが、本当に緊張しているんですが
Ah, I'm nervous, I'm really nervous
ずっとみんな近くで応援してて下さい！
But please keep supporting me from nearby!
リツイートもよろしくお願いします！
Please retweet as well!
Database Database
Just living in the Database
Woah oh
It doesn't even matter if there is no hope
As the madness of the system grows
Crack in the key
But we know we've been longing for this
Cut it out the plot that deceives you
Drop the rebel sound
Shut the system down
Reveal the never-found
いつか化けたとしても
Even if I were to be disguised someday
虚構とも現実とも
Whether it's fiction or reality
見えるガレキの中で
In the rubble that I see
戦い続けるだけ
I'll just keep on fighting
Yeah get them all from bigger heads
Yeah you get them all from bigger heads
重なる世界で
In the overlapping worlds
たぎる心に火を灯して
Light a fire in my boiling heart
Database, Database
Just living in the Database, wow wow
The wall of pure fiction's cracking in my head
And the addiction of my world disspreads in the...
Database, Database
I'm struggling in the Database, wow wow
It doesn't matter if there is no hope
Just say wow wow
Hey wait a minute, what happened? The data's wrong! Come on!
ヤバッつめ割れた
Oh no, my nail's cracked
グルーで補修した
I repaired it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感
Just that gives me a sense of accomplishment
大事なのは自分
What's important is to
かわいがること
cherish yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ他人も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others either
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because the truth is you're crazy
能ある鷹はそう
A clever hawk, you know
見えないとこにピック隠すんです
hides its pick where it can't be seen
想像に一生懸命
Working hard on imagination
現実は絶体絶命
Reality is a desperate situation
1分前だよー！
It's one minute to go!
緊張して！
I'm so nervous!
よろしくお願いします！
Please take care of us!
頑張ろう！
Let's do our best!
So many 不安な日だってあるけど
There are many anxious days, but
メーデー 振り切っていって
Mayday, shake it off and go
いつでも全力で夢見て
Always dreaming with all my might
その分全力で眠って
And sleeping with all my might to match
ヤバッ虹やせた
Oh no, the rainbow's faded
超しつこくて困った
It's so persistent, I'm troubled
それだけでなんで敗北感
Why does just that give me a sense of defeat?
妥協せずに目標
Aim for the target without compromise
下方修正して
revised downwards
十難を臨機応変に
handle ten difficulties flexibly
逃避行が勝ち
fleeing is a win
Please don't say you are lazy
だって本当はcrazy
Because the truth is you're crazy
SAKAMATA CHLOE BIRTHDAY LIVE 2024
ふぅー、ライブの時間か...
Phew, is it time for the live...?
ん？あれ？おらっ？
Hmm? Wait? Huh?
うわーっ！きのこ生えてるー！あたまからー！
Waaah! Mushrooms are growing! From my head!
え、うわ、何これ！？
Eh, uwa, what is this!?
え、何これ、何これ、何これ何これ？
Eh, what is this, what is this, what is this, what is this?
ま、いいか。ん。
Well, whatever. Yeah.
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
うまうまうま。うまうまうま。
Yum yum yum. Yum yum yum.
みんな！今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！めっちゃ緊張してるんで、応援してください！
Everyone! Thank you for coming today! I'm really nervous, so please support me!
One, two, 準備はOK?
One, two, are you ready?
手に付くはしご 全部壊しちゃっていいじゃん
Is it okay to break all the ladders in my hands?
どうせ何が変わるわけじゃない
It's not like anything's going to change anyway.
毎日毎日 はしゃごう 未来
Let's have fun every day, for the future!
ハイ! ハイ! ハイ! ハイ! 行くぞー!
High! High! High! High! Let's go!
Yes, 肯定 曖昧 ドシビレ
Yes, affirmation, ambiguity, so exciting.
ルリララ 弱まっていたってさ しょうがないじゃん
Lulilala, even if I'm getting weaker, it's no use.
やめて おいて せめて 確かめて
Stop it, leave it, at least make sure.
メーデー まるで足りないや
Mayday, it's like it's not enough at all.
弾けだす フレーズ 時は待って
The phrases are bursting, time is waiting.
ほらほら 楽しいことしたもん勝ち
Look, look, the one who has fun wins!
探しに行くんだ 刹那トリップ
I'm going to find it, Setsuna Trip.
飛べない わけない まだ内緒の ハートにダイブ
I can't not fly, dive into my still secret heart.
脇目も振らず 出たとこ勝負
Without looking aside, leave it to chance.
痛い手 いたいわ しない
The painful hand, I won't let it hurt.
息急げ 全開走行
Breathe fast, full-speed running.
醒めても 冷めても その刹那 飼い慣らせ
Even if I wake up or cool down, tame that moment.
そろそろ 本能 限界走行
It's about time, instinct, limit-running.
さあさあ どっぷり はまっちゃおう
Now, now, let's get completely hooked.
ふわふわり もうちょっと ふらふらり もうちょっと
Fluffy, a little more. Dizzy, a little more.
甘えて あらあらよ ちょっと ベイビー
Spoil me, oh my, a little bit, baby.
きっと 発展性も 何もある
Surely there's development and everything.
毎日毎日 凝りないな
Every day, every day, never learning.
早送り 模様 過ぎゆく日々
Fast-forward pattern, the passing days.
まだまだ やって こうやって 溺れたいんだ
Still, doing it like this, I want to drown.
いかんせん 不完全 トリップガール
Anyway, incomplete, Trip Girl.
困る 困る 踊り狂ってる リアルにパン
I'm in trouble, I'm in trouble, dancing crazily, real punch.
抗え きっと トリップガール
Resist it, surely, Trip Girl.
迷路 迷路 色々に紛れて
Maze, maze, getting lost in various things.
裏をかき 明日走る走行
Outsmart them, tomorrow's running.
振らふり 振らふり 耳を塞ぎ 聞こえない
Swaying, swaying, covering my ears, I can't hear.
完備の 完備の 夢見る走行
Perfect, perfect, dream-seeing running.
そこに 縁があると信じて
Believing that there's a connection there.
頑張るだけ 損じゃ なんとなく 察しちゃうじゃん
Just working hard is a loss, somehow I've sensed it.
生まれた時にさ 配られていた手札が
The hand I was dealt when I was born.
弱かったら 終わりだって 先なんて 知れてるって
If it's weak, it's over, and the future is already known.
覆しちゃいなよ って あー、もう！
Overturn it! ...Ah, geez!
まだ待って いらんない わけだって
I can't wait anymore, because...
手札なんて 自分次第なんだって
The hand you have depends on yourself.
いつまで 夢に逃げてるんでしょ
How long are you going to keep running to your dreams?
そろそろ はよ起きる 時間だろ
It's about time to wake up, isn't it?
目を醒ませ 刹那トリップ
Wake up, Setsuna Trip.
飛べない わけない いま眩しい リアルにダイブ
I can't not fly, dive into the now dazzling reality.
脇目も振らず 逃げずに勝負
Without looking aside, fight without running.
絶対 いたいわ しない
I'll definitely never let it hurt.
覚悟決めて 駆け抜けろ
Make up your mind and run through!
わっくわっくわっくわん！
Waku waku waku wan!
秘密結社holoXの掃除担当、沙花叉クロヱです！
I'm Sakamata Chloe, in charge of cleaning for Secret Society holoX!
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
ということで、今日は沙花叉の誕生日に来てくれてありがとー！
So, thank you all for coming to Sakamata's birthday today!
刹那トリップ歌わせていただきましたー！
I just sang 'Setsuna Trip'!
なんか、ちょっと頭がぷあぷあする気がするんですけど
I feel like my head is a bit fuzzy, though.
気のせいだよね？気のせいだよね？
It's just my imagination, right? Right?
引き続き、飼育員さんたちと一緒にこのライブを楽しんでいけたらなと思うので
I'd like to continue enjoying this live together with all the Interns,
よかったらハッシュタグとかでもね
so if you'd like, please tweet using the hashtag and all that.
あのツイートしてもらえたら嬉しいなと思います！
It would make me really happy!
では、このあとお着替えしちゃうので
Now, I'm going to change clothes after this,
ちょっと見ない、見ないでくださいね！
so please don't, don't look, okay?
やめてくださいよ！やだ！
Stop it! No!
じゃ、着替えます！ちょっと、見ないで！
Okay, I'm going to change! Hey, don't look!
あっち行って！あっち行って！
Go away! Go away!
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's shining.
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal.
パレパレパレ 探しに行く
Pare-pare-pare, let's go search.
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start.
皆様、盛り上がっていきましょう！
Everyone, let's get excited!
Our Bright Parade
作詞・作曲・編曲 堀江晶太
Lyrics, Comp., & Arr.: Shota Horie
ただ 独り言綴った
I just wrote down some monologues.
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted to begin.
遠く グラデーションに灯った
A distant gradation lit up.
それは 眩しすぎたままで
It remained far too dazzling.
それは 優しすぎる思い出
It's a memory that's far too kind.
もっと近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず結び合った
We were connected unexpectedly.
ほら今 迷い子は僕らになった
Look, now we've become the lost children.
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's shining.
悔しさも愛おしさも 全部おいで
Come along with all your regrets and affections.
風 夢 羽 飛び立つさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we'll take flight.
囁かな彩りばかり 終わりなき兆し
Only modest colors, signs that never end.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張るよ
I'm proud that I found you.
ここから これから
From here, from now on.
まだ 頼りない予感を
Sing about this still-unreliable premonition,
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing it—it's nothing to be ashamed of.
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can solve.
いつかまた会えるおまじない
A charm to meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まったストーリー
The story that began from zero that day.
数えきれない言の葉
Countless words.
数えるような思いじゃないさ
It's not a feeling you can count.
ほら今 僕らをひとつと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one.
パレパレパレ 美しいんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's beautiful.
許し合える切なさ 夜は開けてく
Sadness of forgiving, the night is breaking.
雨 晴れ 晴れ また隣 空
Rain, sun, sun, the sky next to us again.
相応しい旅路とは 君と歩くことさ
The right journey is one walked with you.
君と歩くことなんだ
It's all about walking with you.
ただいま も 聞けば
If I hear 'I'm home,'
おかえりって叫ぶよ
I'll shout back 'Welcome back.'
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's shining.
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
It's you and me who fill the darkness.
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's shining.
悔しさも愛おしさも 全部おいで
Come along with all your regrets and affections.
風 夢 羽 飛び立つさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we'll take flight.
囁かな彩りばかり 終わりなき兆し
Only modest colors, signs that never end.
君と飛び込んでいこう 素敵なスタートさ
Let's dive in with you, it's a wonderful start.
ここから これから
From here, from now on.
この空がトリガー
作詞 指原莉乃 作曲 塚田耕平
Kono Sora ga Trigger
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara, Comp.: Kohei Tsukada
眩しい太陽を見上げたとき
When I looked up at the dazzling sun.
君に会いたくなった
I wanted to see you.
あの空がトリガー
That sky was the trigger
恋人がいるって 最初から知ってた
I knew from the start that you had a lover
話の合う ただの友達
Just a friend I could talk to
君に勧められた 映画の半券って
The ticket stub for the movie you recommended...
なんとなく外せない
I somehow can't bring myself to throw it away
向かいの方向き 君と目が合った
Looking across at you, our eyes met
今日こそ 二人の赤い糸
Surely today, the red thread between us...
切り離す 意地悪ね
...will be cut. How mean
青い空が綺麗だった日 あの日を忘れてない
I haven't forgotten that day when the blue sky was so beautiful
目に映るものすべて
Everything that reflects in my eyes...
これは君を想いつづく歌 私だけの青春
This is a song about thinking of you, my own private youth
あの空がトリガーだったよ
That sky was the trigger
君が好きだ
I love you
あのバンドがついに ツアーするって一応
That band is finally going on tour, so just in case...
2枚で申し込む
I applied for two tickets
あの映画はどこで 行ったのかな 集中
I wonder where that movie went. Focus
できず 誰かの横顔とか
I couldn't, looking at someone's side profile...
気にしたの きっとそう
...and worrying about it. Surely that's it
君は何も気づいていない あの日の空模様も
You haven't noticed anything, not even the state of the sky that day
君には いつもの空
To you, it's just the usual sky
愛おしくも見つけたら 誰に教えるのでしょう
If you find something dear, who would you tell?
シャッターの音が響いた
The sound of the shutter echoed
行方はどこ
Where is it headed?
さあ 向かっていくか 坂道を
Now, shall I head up the slope?
恋を 曖昧にごまかす
My love, I vaguely cover it up
この想い 伝えちゃダメとわかっている
I know I shouldn't convey these feelings
だけど だけど だけど だけど
But... but... but... but...
心にずっと君がいる
You are always in my heart
青い空が綺麗だった日 私だけが覚えて
I'm the only one who remembers that day the blue sky was beautiful
君は誰かを想う
You are thinking of someone else
なのに勝手に好きでごめんね 私このままでいい
And yet, I'm sorry for loving you on my own. I'm fine like this
空しか知らない この恋
This love that only the sky knows
秘密にして
Keep it a secret
君と二人で あの日会ったこと
The fact that the two of us met that day...
言わないから 想っていたい
...I won't say it, because I want to keep loving you
サラバ、愛しき悲しみたちよ
Farewell, My Dear Sorrows
行くの？
Are you going?
行かないの？
Are you not going?
言っちゃえばいいじゃん
Why don't you just say it?
言えないよ
I can't say it
いたいよ煩いよ言えない
It hurts, it's noisy, I can't say it
表だ 裏だって殺しのクエスチョン
Front or back, it's a killer question
だけどどうしたって何もかも台無し
But no matter what, everything is ruined
Aha! Diggi-diggi... Aha! Diggi-down
見ざる
See no evil
言わざる
Speak no evil
聞かざるでござる
Hear no evil, that's the way
君子危うきに近寄らずです
A wise man keeps away from danger
俺がされたら止めたくなります
If it were me, I'd want to stop
だったら許す だったら笑え
Then forgive, then smile
心の声が木霊する
The voice of my heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気なくらいの夜明けに
To an audaciously bright dawn
行かないで
Don't go
泣かないで
Don't cry
サラバ 奇蹟を脱ぎ捨てて
Farewell, cast off your miracles
勇気の声を振り絞れ
Muster your voice of courage
自分と呼ぶ名の愛を知るために
To know the love that bears your own name
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep
迷える心の叫びを
Let out the cry of your wandering heart
振り返れば我らの世界はまだ
Looking back, our world has only
始まったばかりだ
just begun
寂しい思いさせてんじゃねえよ
Don't go making me feel lonely
やるの サボるの サボればいいじゃん
To work or slack, slacking is fine too
そんあ嘘でも まさかの呼吸
Even if it's a lie, an unexpected breath
褒めてますから 全力で
I'm praising you, with all my might
そしてどこまでも続く夢を見た
And I saw a dream that goes on forever
天使が舞い降りてきた
An angel came dancing down
そしてどこまでも続く空の下
And beneath a sky that goes on forever
自由になりたい
I want to be free
One, Two and Three, Four, Five
Hands up Stand up Free your soul
Hands up and Make sunrise!
Aha! Do-it, Do-it... Aha! Do-it-now
心の声が木霊する
The voice of my heart echoes
涙と希望のカーニバル
A carnival of tears and hope
生意気なくらいの夜明けに
To an audaciously bright dawn
揺らすんだ
Shake it
進むんだ
Move forward
サラバ 奇蹟を脱ぎ捨てて
Farewell, cast off your miracles
勇気の声を振り絞れ
Muster your voice of courage
自分と呼ぶ名の愛を知るために
To know the love that bears your own name
眠れない羊の群れよ
O flock of sleepless sheep
迷える心の叫びを
Let out the cry of your wandering heart
振り返れば我らの世界はまだ
Looking back, our world has only
始まったばかりだ
just begun
Aha! Diggi-diggi... Aha! Diggi-down
Aha! Do-it, Do-it... Do it now!
はい、というわけで、アワーブライトパレード、この空がトリガー、サラバ...
Alright, so that was 'Our Bright Parade', 'Kono Sora ga Trigger', and 'Saraba'...
「サラバ、愛しき悲しみたちよ」でした！
That was "Farewell, My Dear Sorrows"!
どうだったみんな？
How was it, everyone?
どうでした？どうでした？
How did you like it? How did you like it?
「アワ・ブライト・パレード」は、沙花叉が
For "Our Bright Parade," it was the first
初めてジャケットに参加した全体曲で、思い入れがあって。
group song with me on the cover, so I'm attached to it.
一人で歌うのは緊張したし、
Singing it alone made me nervous,
声震えてませんでした？大丈夫だったかな？
and was my voice shaking? I hope it was okay.
「この空がトリガー」はイコラブさんの曲で、
"Kono Sora ga Trigger" is an =LOVE song,
ザ・王道アイドル！って感じの曲なんですが、
and it's such a classic idol song,
似合ってたかな？
did it suit me?
ね、似合ってた？どうだった？
Did it suit me? How was it?
どうだった？
How was it?
そして「サラバ、愛しき悲しみたちよ」、
And about "Farewell, My Dear Sorrows",
ホロックスって戦隊モノ感ありません？
doesn't HoloX have a Sentai (superhero) vibe?
あのヘルメットのせいかもしれないけど、
Maybe it's because of that helmet, but anyway,
戦隊モノっぽい曲を歌って踊りたいなと思ってて。
I've always wanted to sing and dance to a Sentai-style song.
どうでしたか？
What did you think?
似合ってた？最高だった？ありがとう！
Did it suit me? It was the best? Thank you!
ね、わかるよね？わかるよね？同じ、わかるよね？
You get it, right? We're on the same page!
やっぱそう思ったんですよね。自分的にも...
I thought so too. Personally, I think...
似合ってて、いい感じにできたんじゃないかな。
it suited me and went pretty well.
ではですね、
So then,
そう、あのヘルメットね。ではですね、
right, that helmet. Anyway,
ちょっと何か、変なぽよぽよ感というか、
that weird floaty feeling, or rather,
酔いも落ち着いてきたような感じがしますし、
my dizziness seems to have settled down,
このあとも引き続きゲストパート行きたいと思いますので、
so we'll continue with the guest segment now.
応援よろしくお願いします！
Please keep cheering us on!
みんな、よらちゃんだよ！
Everyone, it's Yorachan!
では。
Here we go.
黒い羊
Black Sheep
信号は青なのか それとも緑なのか どっちなんだ?
Is the traffic light blue, or is it green? Which one is it?
あやふやなものは はっきりさせたい
I want to make vague things clear
夕暮れの商店街の 雑踏を通り抜けるのが面倒で
It's such a hassle to walk through the evening shopping district crowds
踏切を渡って 遠回りして帰る
So I cross the tracks and take the long way home
放課後の教室は苦手だ その場にいるだけで分かり合えてるようで
I hate classrooms after school, as if just being there means we understand each other
話し合いにならないし 白けてしまった僕は無口になる
No one really talks, and once things get cold, I just shut up
言いたいこと言い合って 解決しようなんて 楽天的すぎるよ
Saying we can solve everything just by talking... that's way too optimistic
誰かがため息をついた
Somebody let out a sigh
そう それが本当の声だろう
Yeah, that's probably their real voice
黒い羊 そうだ 僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, that's right... everything would be fine if only I was gone
そうすれば 止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろ?
Then the clock hands that stopped would start moving again, wouldn't they?
全員が納得する そんな
A solution that everyone
答えなんかあるものか
would be happy with? As if such a thing exists
反対が僕だけなら いっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one against it, just ignore me already
みんなから説得される方が居心地悪くなる
Being persuaded by everyone just makes me feel more uncomfortable
目配せしてる仲間にゃ
To my comrades who exchange glances
僕は厄介者でしかない
I'm nothing but a nuisance
真っ白な群れに 悪目立ちしてる
I stand out in the pure white herd
自分だけが 真っ黒な羊
I'm the only jet-black sheep
と言ったって同じ色に 染まりたくないんだ
Even if they say that, I don't want to be dyed the same color
薄暗い部屋の灯りを つけるタイミングって一体いつなんだ?
When exactly is the right time to turn on the light in a dim room?
スマホには愛のない 過去だけが残ってる
In my smartphone, only a past without love remains
人間関係の答え合わせなんか 特にできもしないし
I can't even double-check the answers to human relationships
そこにいなければよかったと 後悔する
I just regret that I shouldn't have been there
実際の大半は 思うようにはいかなくて
In reality, most things don't go the way you want
納得できないことばかりだし 諦めろと諭されてきたけど
It's all things I can't accept, though I've been told to just give up
それならやっぱ 納得なんかしないまま その度に何度も唾を吐いて
If that's the case, I'll refuse to accept it and spit at it every single time
噛み付いちゃいけませんか?
Is it wrong for me to bite back?
No No No No
全部 僕のせいだ
It's all my fault
黒い羊 そうだ 僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, that's right... everything would be fine if only I was gone
そうすれば 止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろ?
Then the clock hands that stopped would start moving again, wouldn't they?
全員が納得する そんな
A solution that everyone
答えなんかあるものか
would be happy with? As if such a thing exists
反対が僕だけなら いっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one against it, just ignore me already
みんなから説得される方が居心地悪くなる
Being persuaded by everyone just makes me feel more uncomfortable
目配せしてる仲間にゃ
To my comrades who exchange glances
僕は厄介者でしかない
I'm nothing but a nuisance
分かってるよ
I know that
白い羊なんて僕は絶対なりたくないんだ
I absolutely never want to be a white sheep
そうなった瞬間に僕は僕じゃなくなってしまうよ
The moment that happens, I'll stop being myself
周りと違う
Because of being different from those around me
そのことで誰かに迷惑かけたか?
Have I caused anyone any trouble?
髪の毛を染めろという大人は何が気に食わない?
What do the adults who tell me to dye my hair dislike so much?
反逆の象徴にでもなるとでも思っているのか?
Do they think I'll become a symbol of rebellion or something?
自分の色
My own color
とは違う それだけで厄介ものか OH
Is different, does that alone make me a nuisance? OH
自らの真実を捨て白い羊のフリをする者よ
Those who discard their own truth and pretend to be white sheep
黒い羊を見つけ指を指して笑うのか
Will you find the black sheep and point and laugh?
それならば僕はいつだって
If that's the case, then I'll always
それでも僕はいつだって
Even so, I'll always
ここで悪目立ちしてよう
Stay right here and stand out like a sore thumb
コズミック・フローと
Cosmic Float
瞬きの隙間 こぼれてく Dreamin'
In the space of a blink, the dreaming spills out
一粒残さず 集めてギャラクシー
Collect it all, not a single drop left, Galaxy
(FLASH FLASH) 浮かべて
(FLASH FLASH) Float it up
モノローグ 夢に見たロマンチカ
A monologue, the romantica I saw in my dreams
(SHAKE SHAKE) かき混ぜ
(SHAKE SHAKE) Stir it up
溶かすんだ ファンタジー リアルを上書き
Melt it away, Fantasy, overwriting reality
うららかに光る音色が
The bright, shining timbre
おいで 誘い出すよ
Come, I'll lead the way
うたかたに消えないでシンフォニー
Don't vanish like bubbles, Symphony
つかまえたい
I want to catch it
Planet Love!
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
退屈にコズミックパーティ
A cosmic party for boredom
(シャララララ...)
(Sha-la-la-la-la...)
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
(シャララララ...)
(Sha-la-la-la-la...)
曖昧に揺れるフェイバリット
Vaguely swaying favorites
ミントグリーンの風と
With the mint green wind
サイドブルーの芳した
And the fragrance of side blue
生まれた恋 内緒で今夜
A love that's born, tonight in secret
持ち出そうか
Shall we take it out?
(FLASH FLASH) 繋げた
(FLASH FLASH) Connected
フィルムを 視線の空に透かしてみたら
Looking through the film at the sky in my gaze
(SHAKE SHAKE) 願いと
(SHAKE SHAKE) A wish and
世界が 目を解け 踊りだすトワイライト
The world, eyes unravelling, a dancing twilight
指先に乱反射込めた
Diffused reflection held in my fingertips
愛に 触れるメロディ
A melody touching love
まばたきに咲かせたイメージで
With the image made to bloom in a blink
口ずさむフレーズ
A phrase hummed to oneself
Planet Love!
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
退屈にコズミックパーティ
A cosmic party for boredom
揺らめく旋律は今
The swaying melody is now
シグナル
A signal
星座が散りばめていく きらめきと遊ぶの
The constellations scattering, playing with the sparkles
Planet Love!
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
退屈にコズミックパーティ
A cosmic party for boredom
Swing! Swing! Swing! Yeah!
曖昧に揺れたいフィーリン
I want to sway in ambiguity, that's my feelin'
クロノスタシス
Chronostasis
作詞・作曲 佐藤千亜妃
Lyrics and Composition by Chiaki Sato
コンビニエンスストアで 5 am エネルの缶ビール買って
At the convenience store at 5 AM, buying a can of beer...
君と夜の散歩 時計の針は12時を指してる
A night walk with you, the clock hands point to 12.
クロノスタシスって知ってる？ 知らないと君が言う
"Do you know what chronostasis is?" you ask, "I don't."
時計の針が止まって見える 現象のことだよ
It's the phenomenon where the clock hands appear to stop.
ホリデイズ・ミッドナイト 少し汗ばんだ
Holidays Midnight, a little sweaty...
手のひらが子供みたいな体温
My palms have the temperature of a child's.
誰も知らない場所に行きたい 誰も知らない秘密を知りたい
I want to go somewhere no one knows, I want to know secrets no one knows.
街灯の下で君の髪が
Under the streetlight, your hair...
ゆらゆら揺れて 夢のようで見惚れて
Gently swaying, I'm entranced as if in a dream.
ゆらゆら揺れて 溶かしている
Gently swaying, melting into it.
ホリデイズ・ミッドナイト 今夜だけ忘れてよ
Holidays Midnight, just for tonight, forget...
家まで帰る道
...the way back home.
なんかさ ちょっとさ いい感じ
Somehow, it feels a little nice.
街灯の下で君の影が
Under the streetlight, your shadow...
ゆらゆら揺れて 夢のようで見惚れて
Gently swaying, I'm entranced as if in a dream.
ゆらゆら揺れて 溶かしている
Gently swaying, melting into it.
歩く速度が違うから BPM 84 に合わせて
Because our walking speeds are different, I match the BPM of 84...
君と夜の散歩 それ以上何も言わないで
...and take a night walk with you. Please don't say anything more.
クロノスタシスって知ってる？ 知らないと君が言う
"Do you know what chronostasis is?" you ask, "I don't."
時計の針が止まって見える 現象のことだよ
It's the phenomenon where the clock hands appear to stop.
ゆらゆら揺れて 夢のようで見惚れて
Gently swaying, I'm entranced as if in a dream.
ゆらゆら揺れて 溶かしている
Gently swaying, melting into it.
コンビニエンスストアで 5 am エネルの缶ビール買って
At the convenience store at 5 AM, buying a can of beer...
君と夜の散歩 時計の針は12時を指してる
A night walk with you, the clock hands point to 12.
クロノスタシスって知ってる？ 知らないと君が言う
"Do you know what chronostasis is?" you ask, "I don't."
時計の針が止まって見える 現象のことだよ
It's the phenomenon where the clock hands appear to stop.
ララハ...
La-la-ha...
いぇーい！みんな、どうだった？ 楽しんでくれましたか？
Yay! Everyone, how was it? Did you enjoy it?
なんか、後ろにいる変なのも一緒に楽しんでくれてたみたいで
It seems like that weird thing behind me was also enjoying it.
めちゃめちゃ自己主張激しくてすみません。ちょっと見苦しかったと思うんですけど。
Sorry it was so self-assertive, it must have been a bit of an eyesore.
はい。なんか変な感じするね。頭がぼーっとするような。
Yes... I feel kind of strange. Like my head is fuzzy.
あのキノコが悪かったのかな？
Was it because of that mushroom?
さっき変なキノコ食べちゃったんですけど、みんなも拾い食いダメだよ。
I ate a weird mushroom earlier, but you guys shouldn't scavenge for food!
道端から拾って食べちゃダメだからね。
Don't pick up things from the side of the road and eat them.
ということで、まだまだライブは続きます。沙花叉、これからも頑張って歌って...
And with that, the live concert continues. Chloe's going to keep doing her best singing...
全力で踊りますので 応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll be dancing with all my might, so please support me!
よっしゃーいくぞー！
Alright, let's go!
ということで。
So then.
それでは、歌わせていただきたいと思います。
Now, I'd like to sing.
アイドル！
Idol!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Stirring up the media with an invincible smile
アイドル
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Idol
Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Wanna know her secret, so mysterious
抜けてるところさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are part of her charm
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You are a perfect, lying...
天才的なアイドル様
genius idol
今日何食べた？ 好きな本は？
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you were to go out, where would you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
I haven't eaten anything. That's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Whatever I'm asked, I just dodge and weave.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So coolly, yet so brilliantly
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
The secrets that seem visible but aren't, taste like honey.
あれもないないない これもないないない
Not that, no, no, no. Not this, no, no, no.
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？ さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's the person? Come on, answer me!
「誰かを好きになるなんて私分からなくてさ」
“I don't really know what it's like to fall in love with someone.”
嘘か本当か知り得ない そんな言葉に
To those words, whether they're lies or the truth, no one can know,
また一人堕ちる また好きにさせる
Another person falls, made to love you again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone finds their eyes stolen away
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
By you, the perfect and ultimate idol
金劫際現れない
A star that will never appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
The reincarnation of the brightest star.
ああ その笑顔で「愛してる」で
Ah, with that smile, with an "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
You captivate everyone and anyone.
その瞳が その言葉が
Those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全な愛
Even if they're lies, they're perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special.
我々は端からおまけです
We are just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're just Supporting Role B, there to make the star shine.
全てがあの子のおかげな
Everything is thanks to that girl—
わけない 洒落臭い 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
As if! How annoying. There's no way there's no envy or jealousy.
これはネタじゃない からこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is exactly why it's unforgivable.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
I can't forgive you if you're not perfect.
自分を許せない
I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't acknowledge anyone but you, who are stronger than anyone.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Truly the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses can be found.
一番星を宿している
You harbor the brightest star.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never, ever show your weak points.
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing the parts people don't want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
You must be one of a kind, or it's no good.
それこそ本物の愛
That's what true love is.
特意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Boiling up the media with your signature smile.
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Just this secret, I'll keep it hidden forever.
「愛してる」って嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on the lie of "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
The sweat that flows is a beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
These eyelids that hide rubies.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing, dancing, and soaring, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Having never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
Nor having ever loved anyone,
そんな私の嘘がいつか
Those lies of mine, I hope that someday
本当になること信じてる
They will become the truth.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
Someday, I'll surely get it all.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I'm a greedy idol like that.
等身大でみんなのこと
In my true self, I want to properly
ちゃんと愛したいから
Love everyone,
今日も嘘をつくの
So I'll tell lies again today.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Wishing for the day these words will someday come true.
それでもまだ
Even so,
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
I still couldn't say it to you and only you,
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie.
「愛してる」
“I love you.”
P.E.T.
作詞・作曲：DECO*27 / 編曲：Rockwell
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27 / Arrangement: Rockwell
繋いだ真っ赤な糸が
The bright red thread connecting us
嬉しくてよしよししちゃう
Makes me so happy, I want to pet you
どこにも行かないように縛って
Tie you up so you can't go anywhere
ほら私だけに寄り添って
Look, just stay close to me
良い子に出来てたのにな
I was being such a good girl
よそ見とべったり手垢
Looking away and covered in sticky handprints.
今すぐ洗わなきゃ
I have to wash them off right now.
誰になでなでされたのバッチィね
Who gave you pets? How dirty.
愛のメトロノーム増して
The metronome of love is speeding up,
フレフレして見せてよ 期待の
So show me your wagging tail, just as I expect.
どうしちゃったの？ 絶対絶対絶対好きでしょ？
What's wrong? You definitely, definitely, definitely love me, right?
どうしちゃったの？ いっぱいいっぱいいっぱい愛して
What's wrong? Love me more, more, more.
私だけの君じゃなきゃ
If you're not mine and mine alone,
ねえ嫌だよ
Hey, I won't like it.
ねえ君は
Hey, you,
ねえ誰に懐いてるんだろう
Hey, who are you becoming attached to?
どうしちゃったの？ 絶対絶対絶対好きでしょ？
What's wrong? You definitely, definitely, definitely love me, right?
大好きでしょ
You love it, right?
どうしちゃったの いっぱい いっぱい いっぱい 愛して
What's wrong? Love me more and more and more.
私だけの君じゃなきゃね 嫌だよ
It's no good if you're not mine alone.
ねぇ 君は ねぇ 誰になついてるんだろう
Hey, who are you getting attached to?
ねぇ 私が君にあげた首輪はしたまま
Hey, keep on the collar I gave you.
おはようってキスをしたら
If we kiss and say good morning...
さわり合って 二人の時間
Touching each other, our time together.
なーのに私だけじゃ足りないの？
But am I not enough on my own?
これが俗に言う 執着か
Is this what's commonly called obsession?
あいつがいけないんだね
It's that person's fault, isn't it?
アドレからの通知音 忍び音
The notification sound from 'Adore', a stealthy sound.
壊しちゃっていいかしら
Is it okay if I break it?
言い訳ばっかり 見苦しいわ
Just excuses, it's unsightly.
あれもこれも煩わしいわ
This and that, it's all so bothersome.
お仕置きしちゃわなきゃね きいてるの？
I have to punish you. Are you listening?
どうしちゃったの ずっと ずっと ずっと 好きだよ
What's wrong? I'll love you forever, forever, forever.
どうしちゃったの ちゃんと ちゃんと ちゃんと 愛して
What's wrong? Love me properly, properly, properly.
君以外なんていらない ねぇ 嫌だよ
I don't need anyone but you. No way.
ねぇ 君は 私のものなんだよ
Hey, you are mine.
どうしちゃったの ずっと ずっと ずっと 好きだよ
What's wrong? I'll love you forever, forever, forever.
どうしちゃったの ちゃんと ちゃんと ちゃんと 愛して
What's wrong? Love me properly, properly, properly.
君以外なんていらない ねぇ 嫌だよ
I don't need anyone but you. No way.
ねぇ 君は 私のものなんだよ
Hey, you are mine.
ねぇ 君が 裏切るなら わかってるよね
Hey, if you betray me, you know what happens, right?
右左右君右下上目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right-Left-Right, you, Bottom-Right-Up eyes, so sparkly and cute!
タイガー！サイバー！ファイバー！ダイバー！バイバー！ジャージャー！
Tiger! Cyber! Fiber! Diver! Viber! Jya-jya!
あれやこれや言ったって 結局世はごめんじゃん
No matter what's said, in the end the world says 'sorry'.
ずっとそばにいるなんて 正直ムリゲーってじゃん
Being by your side forever is honestly an impossible game.
あの頃よりも上なんて 大体背伸びのフリじゃん
Being better than back then is mostly just pretending to be taller.
マヂな話噛んだって リュックの中身パンパンじゃん
Even if I mess up serious talk, my backpack is stuffed full.
でも でも 君となら
But, but, if it's with you...
目と目 すぐで 一途に 心掴み その中に
Eyes meeting instantly, wholeheartedly catching your heart inside.
見て 頭の先から爪まで ウーガのナチュラルスタイル
Look, from the top of my head to my nails, Wuga's natural style.
調子に乗ってあちこんで 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Getting carried away and falling, there are days I cry, but...
さらけらん 触れらん 君だけ 補正あれば撃ち込め
Can't reveal, can't touch, just you. If there's a correction, shoot it in.
爆風 目風は決めたら 文句はこれでないね
If the blast and wind are decided, there are no complaints, right?
右左右君右下上目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right-Left-Right, you, Bottom-Right-Up eyes, so sparkly and cute!
斜め右 あざとさとペロ まじだお めちょかわいい
Slanted right, calculating and sticking out my tongue. Seriously, so cute!
夜更かし 極めて 逆に健康だ！
Staying up late to the extreme, conversely, I'm healthy!
ちっぽけ 卑屈すぎます 炎上だけはカンベンです
Too small and self-deprecating. Please, just no flame wars.
そうは言われても約束できない 好きなことだけ爆速でいたい
Even if you say that, I can't promise. I want to do only what I like at top speed.
わんこも大好きです 今日も生きてて偉いちゃんです
I love puppies too. You're a good kid for living today.
褒められると申し訳ない 期待した潜った人間ですし
I feel bad being praised. I'm just a person who stayed hidden.
でも でも 君だから
But, but, because it's you...
時間は すぐに 一途に 心揺らす 君のために
Time goes by fast, wholeheartedly shaking my heart for you.
ほら 頭の先から爪まで ウーガのナチュラルスタイル
Look, from the top of my head to my nails, Wuga's natural style.
うそじゃん パジャマのままだし 驚く日もあるけど
No way, I'm still in pajamas. There are days I'm surprised, but...
でもいつでも選ぶは君だけ 補正ないけど撃ち抜け
But I'll always choose only you. No correction, but shoot through.
調子に乗ってもいいよね 文句は後で聞きます
It's okay to get carried away, right? I'll listen to complaints later.
右左右君右下上目きゅるんめちょかわ！
Right-Left-Right, you, Bottom-Right-Up eyes, so sparkly and cute!
斜め右 あざとさとペロ まじだお めちょかわいい
Slanted right, calculating and sticking out my tongue. Seriously, so cute!
右左君君右下上目きゅるんめちぇかわ！
Right, left, you, you, bottom right, upward glance, kyurun, so cute!
はぁ、はぁ、もう無理疲れた。
Ah, ah, I'm at my limit, I'm so tired.
あ、あざす。あざす。
Ah, thanks. Thanks.
ということで、えー...
So, um...
『アイドル・ペット』右左君君右下上目
That was 'Idol Pet: Left Right You You Bottom Right
きゅるんめちぇかわでしたー！
Upper Glance Kyurun Mecha-Kawa'!
自分の曲なのに、毎回言えないんですけど...
Even though it's my own song, I can't say it right every time...
はい、いやでも本当にね、あの、頑張ってやりきったんじゃないかなと思って。
Yes, well, but really, I think I did my best to get through it.
ちょっと本当に緊張してたんですけど、『ペット』ぐらいからちょっと緊張飛んできたかなって感じで。
I was really nervous, but from around 'Pet', I feel like the tension started to fade.
あとは楽しむだけな！
Now all that's left is to enjoy it!
最後の曲になっちゃうんですよ、でも。あっという間だった！
But it's already time for the last song. It went by in a flash!
なんて？ごめん、カミカミでごめんって。
What? Sorry, sorry for stumbling over my words.
最後の曲はですね、なんと...
The last song is, actually...
すりぃさんに作曲いただいた新曲になります！イエーイ！
a new song composed by Surii-san! Yay!
この曲はですね、世の中に対する毒がたくさん込められた、
This song contains a lot of poison towards the world,
ちょっとダークな楽曲になっています。
it's a bit of a dark piece.
で、こちらの曲なんですけど、リリースとMVの公開はまだ少し先になってしまうので、
And as for this song, the release and MV premiere are still a little while away,
本日は特別に先行お披露目という形で歌って躍らせていただきたいと思います！
so today I'd like to perform it as a special advance reveal!
もう一回飲んでもいいですか？ごめんなさい。
Can I have one more drink? Sorry.
ありがとうございます。すいません。
Thank you. Sorry.
はい。ということで、では...
Alright. So, then...
最後まで引き続き楽しんでってください。いきますよ、はぁー！
please continue to enjoy until the very end. Here we go, haa!
モードク / 作詞・作曲・編曲：すりぃ
Mo-Doku / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Surii
相談ね はいはい 正論じゃ嫌な連中
Consultation? Yeah, right. People who hate logical arguments.
同情はないない 悪いのアナタ
No sympathy at all. It's your fault.
語彙が足んない 伝わらないわ
Lack of vocabulary. It won't get across.
感情はないない つまんないのよ
No emotions at all. It's so boring.
ドドドコドコドク ドドドコドコドク
Do-do-do-ko-do-ko-doku...
さよならはー もう会わない 興味がないわ
Goodbye. We won't meet again. I'm not interested.
ドドドコドコドク
Do-do-do-ko-do-ko-doku...
はい正解 アタシの勝ち 奪っておいて無駄
Yes, correct. I win. It's useless even if you take it.
結論非効率ダメ
Conclusion: Inefficient, no good.
モードクドク 吐かして頂戴
Mo-Doku-Doku, let me spit it out.
面倒ね アナタの相手
It's a pain, dealing with you.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate.
笑っちゃダメなの？ワレモノね
Am I not allowed to laugh? How fragile.
モードクドク 至って冷静
Mo-Doku-Doku, perfectly calm.
表情も変えないで論破
Winning the argument without changing expression.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate.
笑っちゃダメなの？綺麗なようですね
Am I not allowed to laugh? It seems beautiful.
素敵なドドドコレいミュージック
A wonderful do-do-do-this music.
会社で飲み会 嫌な話
Company drinking party, unpleasant stories.
フラれて行けない あの花火
Getting dumped and can't go to those fireworks.
やたらと冷たい 口調正し
Pointlessly cold tone, correct it.
愛されてきた これが証
I've been loved, this is the proof.
どーでもいいじゃん そんなこと
Who cares about that sort of thing?
行かないでオッケ
It's okay not to go.
どーでもいいじゃん そんなこと
Who cares about that sort of thing?
一人で観れば？
Why don't you watch alone?
どーでもいいじゃん そんなこと
Who cares about that sort of thing?
話が進まない
The conversation isn't going anywhere.
どーでもいいじゃん そんなこと
Who cares about that sort of thing?
証とかかし
Proof and scarecrow...
モードクドク 蓋して融解
Mo-Doku-Doku, seal it and melt.
表面じゃ良い子のフリして
Pretending to be a good kid on the surface.
イラッ イラッ イラッ
Irritated, irritated, irritated.
無視っちゃダメなの？バカだるいね
Am I not allowed to ignore? How stupidly tiresome.
モードクドク 泣かして大変
Mo-Doku-Doku, making you cry is quite a task.
ギャアギャアと五月蝿いなモンスター
Shut up, you noisy monsters.
イラッ イラッ イラッ イラッ
Irritated, irritated, irritated, irritated.
黙ってお願い 無駄に喚いたって
Shut up, please. Even if you shout in vain...
変わるわけないのにどうして
It won't change anything, so why?
結論非効率ダメ
Conclusion: Inefficient, no good.
モードクドク 吐かして頂戴
Mo-Doku-Doku, let me spit it out.
面倒ね アナタの相手
It's a pain, dealing with you.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate.
笑っちゃダメなの？ワレモノね
Am I not allowed to laugh? How fragile.
モードクドク 至って冷静
Mo-Doku-Doku, perfectly calm.
表情も変えないで論破
Winning the argument without changing expression.
嫌い 嫌い 嫌い 嫌い
Hate, hate, hate, hate.
笑っちゃダメなの？綺麗なようですね
Am I not allowed to laugh? It seems beautiful.
素敵なドドドコレいミュージック
A wonderful do-do-do-this music.
少しは反省します バイバイ
I'll reflect a little. Bye-bye.
はーい！ということで『モードク』聴いてくれてありがとうございましたー！
Yes! So thank you for listening to 'Mo-Doku'!
リリースはもうちょい先になりますが、
The release is still a little ways off,
MVも楽しみに待っててください！
but please look forward to the MV as well!
ではですね、ここで恒例の告知があります！
And now, it's time for the usual announcement!
みんな何だろうね、分かんないね、何だろうね？
Everyone's wondering what it is, right?
You have no idea, do you?
うーん、分かんないよね。
Yeah, I bet you don't.
グッズ出ます！
Merch is coming out!
沙花叉クロヱ誕生日記念 2024
Sakamata Chloe Birthday Celebration 2024
はい、沙花叉クロヱ誕生日記念2024ということで、
Yes, for the Sakamata Chloe Birthday Celebration 2024,
パセリママにまたまたお仕立てしていただいたキービジュアルで登場なんですが、
we're featuring a key visual illustrated
once again by Parsley-papa.
パセリママがですね、オリジナルのアイドル衣装を描いてくださったということで、
Parsley-papa drew an original idol outfit for me,
ちょっとグッズの方紹介させてください。こちらです！
so please let me introduce the merch.
Here it is!
アクリルジオラマスタンド
Acrylic Diorama Stand
アクリルジオラマスタンド、こちらはですね、キービジュアルと同じものになっているんですが、
The Acrylic Diorama Stand. This one features
the same art as the key visual,
キノコを食べていつもと様子が違う、王道沙花叉になっちゃったよ、みたいなコンセプトなんですけど、
but the concept is "Sakamata ate a mushroom
and became a classic idol, different from her usual self."
まあ、王道アイドルですよね、元々ね！
Well, I was always a classic idol to begin with!
だから何の問題もないです。ぜひ飾ってください。
So there's no problem at all.
Please put it on display.
めちゃめちゃ可愛いです。はい、そして次こちら！
It's super cute. Alright, and next is this!
ビッグシルエットTシャツ
Big Silhouette T-shirt
ビッグシルエットTシャツ。こちらサイズはフリーサイズになっております。
The Big Silhouette T-shirt.
This comes in a free size.
沙花叉がですね、この胸ポケの部分にいまして、
I'm right here in this chest pocket,
後ろのところとかもね、キノコがどんどん食べられてる感じで、この辺、なんて言ったらいいですかね、にいるんですけど、
and on the back, you can see mushrooms
gradually being eaten over... in this area here.
キノコが徐々に徐々に食べられてってるみたいな感じになってます。
It shows mushrooms being eaten bit by bit.
ちょっとね、コーションテープとかもあったり、さりげないかなっていう感じで、ポケの中にもね、
It's got some caution tape on it for a subtle look,
and even inside the pocket,
実はちょっと刺繍が入ってたりとか、結構凝った作りになっております。
there's actually a little bit of embroidery.
It's quite a detailed design.
沙花叉自身が出すグッズの中では初アパレルということで、
This is the first apparel item I've released
as my own merch,
ぜひとも手に入れてください。そして！
so please be sure to get one. And!
ランダムコスチュームキーホルダー
Random Costume Keyholders
ランダムコスチュームキーホルダー。
The Random Costume Keyholders.
沙花叉の今までの衣装デザインのキーホルダーということで、こちらの4種が入っております。
These keyholders feature my previous costume designs.
There are four types in total.
可愛いでしょ？この衣装ごとにね、ちゃんとタグとかもついてるんです。めちゃめちゃ可愛いんです。
Cute, right? Each costume even comes
with its own tag. They're so adorable.
よかったらぜひコンプしてください。そしてこちら！
Please try to collect them all. And then, this!
クロエきのこのぬいぐるみバッジ
Chloe Mushroom Plush Badge
これですね、これ。今回の目玉商品になっております。
This is the one. This is our featured item for this time.
クロエきのこぬいぐるみバッジ。安全ピン付きで、ちょっとキーホルダーにもバッジにもなるよって感じで、
The Chloe Mushroom Plush Badge.
It has a safety pin, so it can be a keychain or a badge.
いろんなとこにキノコを生やせるようになりますので、ぬいとか、お洋服とか、バッグとかいろんなとこにつけてもらえたら嬉しいと思います。
You'll be able to sprout mushrooms anywhere,
so I'd love for you to pin them on your plushies, clothes, or bags.
皆様も気軽にキノコ生やしてみてください。そしてこちら！
Everyone, please feel free to sprout some mushrooms.
And next!
シチュエーションボイス「握手会」
Situation Voice: "Handshake Event"
今回のボイスはですね、シチュエーションボイスで握手会となっております。
This time, we have a situation voice
of a handshake event.
王道アイドルの沙花叉がする握手会となっておりますね。
It's a handshake event with a classic idol version of me.
この後、特典の方のボイスとですね、ちょっと、何て言うんですかね、比較すると面白いボイスになっているので、
If you compare it to the bonus voice later,
it makes for a pretty interesting listen.
よかったら聞いてみてください。そして、
So please check it out. And,
フルセット買ってくださった方々にはこちらです！
for those who purchase the full set, here's this!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
フルセット購入特典は、沙花叉クロヱ直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード、
The Full Set Purchase Bonus is an Instax-style
bromide card with a handwritten message from me,
そして、特典ボイスの「沙花叉流握手会」ということで、
and a bonus voice titled "Sakamata-style Handshake Event."
さっきのボイスとの違いを楽しんでほしいなっていうボイスと、
I want you to enjoy the difference from the other voice,
あとですね、こちらの、いつものながら数量限定じゃない、直筆メッセージ入りの特典となっておりますので、
and as usual, this isn't a limited quantity item,
so everyone who gets the set will get the handwritten message.
沙花叉が頑張って書かせていただきますので、よろしくお願いいたします。チェックしてね！
I'll do my best to write them all,
so please look forward to it. Check it out!
はい、ということで、改めて「猛毒」ありがとうございました。
Alright, so, thank you once again for "Moudoku."
あの、めちゃめちゃ沙花叉はこの曲が大好きでして、キャッチーだし、ちょっと、なんて言うんですかね、
Um, I really, really love this song.
It's catchy and, how should I put it...
ダークさが本当にあからさまに分かりやすく出てるんですけど、それを曲調でも隠してるっていうところがまた、
the darkness is really obvious and easy to understand,
but it's also hidden within the melody,
ちょっと二面性があっていいなと思っているんで、
which gives it a nice duality.
このなんかさ、見て！ステージとかもさ、猛毒に合いそうでしょ？めちゃめちゃいい感じにできたんじゃないかなと思っているんですよ。
And look at this! Doesn't the stage look
like it suits "Moudoku" too? I think it turned out great.
見てみてー！
Take a look!
はい、猛毒もですね、MVが出たらぜひ聞いてほしいなと思うし、リリースも楽しみに待っててください！
Yes, I hope you'll listen to "Moudoku" when the MV is out,
and please look forward to the release!
ということで皆様ありがとうございました。ぜひとも感想たくさん呟いてください。よろしくお願いします。
So, thank you everyone. Please tweet lots of your thoughts.
I look forward to reading them.
いや、マジで緊張したけど、本当に緊張したけど、
Man, I was seriously nervous, I really was.
でもみんなのコメント見てたらなんかちょっと笑ったりして、元気になってました。ありがとうございます。
But seeing everyone's comments made me laugh
and cheered me up. Thank you so much.
では、また会おうね！バイバイ！
Well then, see you again! Bye-bye!
沙花叉クロヱの不思議なキノコ
Sakamata Chloe and the Mysterious Mushroom